Edward Twitchell Hall papers 1930-1979
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers of Edward Twitchell Hall, 1930-1979
MS 196
Hall, Edward Twitchell
The collection contains Hall's correspondence, field notes, research, writings, and typescripts beginning with his college studies at the University of Arizona and continuing up to 1979.
24.2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Anthropologist, educator, author and consultant.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series.
Series I: Correspondence, 1930-1979
Series II: Career, 1931-1978
Series III: Writings, 1935-1979
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains Hall's correspondence, field notes, research, writings, and typescripts beginning with his college studies at the University of Arizona and continuing up to 1979. Correspondents include Marshall McLuhan, Ralph Linton, Margaret Mead, Erich Fromm, Robert Sommers, and Humphrey Osmund. Along with Erich Fromm's correspondence, is a handwritten essay by Fromm entitled "Age of Anxiety."
Hall's studies of dendrochronology and early Southwestern pottery include school papers, field notes, charts, photographs of pottery sherds, and typescripts of two field reports. One is The Dating of Awatovi, from the Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition of 1937-39; the other is Early Stockaded Settlements in the Governador, New Mexico, from the Columbia University Governador Expedition, 1941.
Reports, logs, notebooks, maps, charts, and snapshots of people and landscapes document Hall's work, Economy of the Truk Islands, 1946. Hall's research in intercultural communication and proxemics is included, as well as papers by others. Most of Hall's writings concern the relationship between culture and communication. Also included are articles, essays, and lectures; as well as typescripts and multiple published copies of his books: The Silent Language, The Hidden Dimension, Handbook for Proxemic Research, The Fourth Dimension in Architecture, and Beyond Culture.
Hall, Edward Twitchell, -- 1911--Archives; McLuhan, Marshall, -- 1911-- Correspondence; Linton, Ralph, -- 1893-1953 -- Correspondence; Mead, Margaret, -- 1901-1978 -- Correspondence; Fromm, Erich, -- 1900-; Sommers, Robert -- Correspondence; Osmund, Humphrey -- Correspondence; Intercultural communication -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Space perception -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Communication -- Cross-cultural studies; Excavations (Archaeology) -- Southwest, New; Anthropological linguistics; Ethnology -- Micronesia -- Chuuk -- Sources Land grants Arizona; Chuuk (Micronesia) -- Social conditions -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Correspondence; Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1930-1979
  Includes: working files, enclosures and related materials such as papers, clippings, pictures.
  - Abbot, Preston S./Human Ecology Fund. 1930-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adair, John. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Air Travel. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alexander, Christopher. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Altman, Irwin (see also Box 33/Folders 2-3). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Anthropological Association. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Anthropologist. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Institute of Architects (AIA). (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Institute of Interior Designers. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ani, Moukhtar. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anthropology Film Center (see Willams, Caroll and John). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Architectural & Engineering News. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Architectural Review (London) and Architecture Research Laboratory, University of Michigan (see Larson, C. Theodore). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arensberg, Conrad M. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Aspen Design Conference (Interior Design Conference in Aspen) and Association for the Study of Man-Environment Relations, Inc. (see Esser, Aristide H.). 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Audy, J. Ralph. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bacon, Edmund. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART), Report. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beier, Ernst G. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Benedict, Ruth. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Berkeley Architecture Department. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Blassingame, Lurton, literary agent for The Hidden Dimension. 1955-1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Blassingame, Lurton, literary agent for The Hidden Dimension. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bohannan, Paul J. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Book Reviews by ETH. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Boutourline, Serge, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Braden, William. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brew, J.O. (see also Box 20/Folders 1-2). (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Bridge/John N. Stalker. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brockman, John/Intermedia. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brodey, Warren. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brookfield Zoo (Chicago Zoological Park/Society). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Building Research Advisory Board (BRAB). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bureau of Standards. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Byers, Paul. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Calhoun, John B. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cantril, Hadley. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Carpenter, Edmund. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Center of Applied Linguisitics. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chapters by ETH in anthologies and Chicago, Department of Urban Renewal (see Department of Urban Renewal, Chicago). (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chicago Talks and Chicago Zoological Park/Society (see Brookfield Zoo). (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chombart de Lauwe, Paul-Henry. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Christian, John J. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clay, Grady. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cleveland, Harlan/Oversees American: Maxwell Graduate School, Syracuse University. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Collier, John Jr. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Commerce, U.S. Department of. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Commission on Law Enforcement and Administration of Justice. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Conference on Anthropology and Mental Health, Palo Alto, California and Conference on the Humanistic Aspects of the City, Ithaca, New York (see Cornell Conference). 1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Congressional Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Congressional Legislation. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cornell Conference: Humanistic Aspects of the City. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cosmos Club and the Cliff Dwellers. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Current Anthropology. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Currie, Leonard Jr. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - D'Andrea, Patricia/ La Confluencia. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Flora. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Martha. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Deere Study (not including Hewitt, see also Box 52). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Deere Study, Hewitt (see also Box 52). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Delbruck, Max. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - De Long, Alton (see also Box 33/Folders 13-14). (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Denver Mayor's Committee on Minorities. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Denver Mayor's Committee on Minorities, Report (see also Box 40/Folder 9). (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Department of Urban Renewal. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Design & Environment. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dewey, Kenneth. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dillon, Wilton. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Doubleday: Hidden Dimension Correspondence from Readers. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Doxiadis, C.A. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Doxiadis: Delos Conference. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Doxiadis: Ekistics. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Doxiadis: World Society for Ekistics. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Drucker, Peter F. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - DeBois, Cora. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dubos, Rene. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - DuFlon, Henry A. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dutch Housing Experts. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Eberhard, John P. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Educational Facilities Laboratories, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R. and Ekistics (see Doxiadis: Ekistics). (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ekman, Paul. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Ekstrand, Lars Henrick. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Encyclopedia of Education and Entenza, John, D. (see the Graham Foundation). (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, Noise Abatement Hearing (see also box 49/Folder 11). 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Envy Group, Report. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Erickson, Frederick d. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Erikson Institute Lectures. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Esser, Aristide. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Estes, Richard. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Ewald, William R., Jr. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eves, Roland. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fawcett Publications, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Felker, Clay. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Field Museum of Natural History. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fisher, Lawrence E. (see also Box 36/Folders 6-7 and Box 37/Folder 1). (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Service Institute, Point IV. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fortas, Abe and The Fourth Dimension in Architecture (see Box 3/Folders 6-7). (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fortune. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Foster, George M. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Frank, Lawrence K. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fried, Marc. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fromm, Eric. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fromm Festschriff. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Galloway, Charles M. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - GAP (Group for Advancement of Psychiatry, Inc.)/Wedge Bryant. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Gibson, James J. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Glenesk, William. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Goffman, Erving. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Goldberg, Bertrand. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Goldfarb, Ronald. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Goldfinger, M. Erno. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Graham Foundation. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Grant, Stephen H. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Greenbie, Barrie B., Grimshaw, Allen D. (see MAP), and Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry (see GAP). (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Guggenheim (John Simon) Foundation. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Activities. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Articles About. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Bibliography to 1979. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Books, Foreign Language Translations. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Curriculum Vita and Resume. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Interviews for Publication, TV etc. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Lectures. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Manuscripts Reviewed. 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Publicity Photos and Releases. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hall, Edward T.: TV and Radio Broadcasts. 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hall, Edward T.: Visiting Professor, Offers and Miscellaneous (see also Box 1/Folder 3, Box 25/ Folder 25, Box 2/Folders 14-15, Box 7/Folder 16, Box 12/Folder 2, Box 15/Folders 14-15, and Box 15/Folder 22). 1930-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hall, Elizabeth. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Halprin, Lawrence and Handbook for Proxemic Research (see Box 13/Folder 23 and Boxes 50-51). (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Harvard Business Review. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Harvard Business School, Contacts. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Harvard Business School, Leatherbee Lectures. 1962 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Haury, Emil W. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Haussamen, Carol W. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Hediger, Heidi. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Hellersberg, Elisabeth Franzen. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Henderson, Donald M. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Herr, Beth Kupper, Heweitt, Willam A. (see Deere Study) and The Hidden Dimension (see Box 22/ Folders 22-23, Box 3/Folder 16, Box 8/Folder 30 and Boxes 44-47. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Hill-Burnett, Jacquetta. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Holt, John. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Holzman, Philip S. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Hood, Robert and Marjorie. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Horizon. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Horsbrugh, Patrick. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - House and Garden, article. 1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hoving, Thomas P.F. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Huden, Daniel and Gudrun M. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hughes, Everett C. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Human Behavior, Interview and Human Ecology Fund 1963-1968 (see Abbot, Preston S.). 1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Hymes, Dell H. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - IBM Laboratory. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, Experimental Course in Self Teaching. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Inland Architect and Institute for Nonverbal Communication Research, Inc. (see Davis, Martha). (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Institute for Psychoanalysis. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - International Communication Association Conference, International Conference on Nonverbal Behavior (Toronto), and International Design Conference (see Aspen Design Conference). (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Invitations Declined. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Inzerilli, Giorgio. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Ittelson, Lane (see also Box 35/Folder 9 and Box 35/Folder 11). (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Ittelson, William H. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Izumi, K./Izumi, Arnott & Sugiyama. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Jackson, John Brickerhoff/ Landscape. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Joffe, Natalie F. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Johnson-Marshall, Percy. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Joint Economic Committee, Subcommittee on Urban Affairs, Hearings (see also Box 48/Folder 7) and Jones, Courtney R. (see Jackson, John Brickerhoff). 1967 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Kahn, Judy. 1930-1979 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Kampelman, Max M. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Katz, Aaron. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Kennedy, Donald A. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Kepes, Gyorgy. (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Key, Mary Ritchie. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Kinesis, interview (see also Davis, Martha), Kloman, William (see Horizon) and Kolbenschlag, Michael (see Human Behavior, interview). (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Kraft, Joseph. (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Kroeber, A.L. (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Kuhn, Ferdinand and Delia. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kunihiro, Masao. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - La Barre, Weston. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Labor Department Talk, La Confluencia (see D'Andrea, Patricia), and Landscape (see Jackson, John Brinckerhoff). 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Larson, C. Theodore. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Larson, Leslie. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lazarus, Ralph E. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lee, Dorothy. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Legal Assistance Foundation of Chicago. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lescher, Robert, Literary Agent for Beyond Culture. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lewis, Ralph Kepler. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Linn, Karl. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Linton, Ralph (see also Box 22/Folder 1-2). (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Little, Kenneth. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Llewelyn-Davies, Richard. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Lomax, Alan. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Lowenthal, David. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Lynch, Kevin. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - MAP (Multiple Analysis Project)/Grimshaw, Alan D. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Marriott, Alice. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Matthew, robert H and Lorna and Maxwell Graduate School, Syracuse University (see Cleveland, Harlan). (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Mayer, Tom. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - McBride, Glen. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - McCarthy, Eugene J. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - McHale, John. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - McInnis, Noel F. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - McLuhan, Marshall. 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - McLuhan, Marshall. 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - McLuhan, Marshall. 1968-- (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - McNickle, Roma, editor for The Hidden Dimension and Beyond Culture. (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Mead, Margaret. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Midwest Research Institute. (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Minnesota, University of and Minnesota International Center. (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. --1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1950-1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: A-H. 1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: I-W. 1969 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: A-I. 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: J-Y. 1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: A-H. 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: I-W. 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: A-J. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: K-U. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence A-L. 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: M-Z. 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: A-K. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: L-V. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Modern Hospital. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Montagu, Ashley; Mulitple Analysis Project, (see MAP). (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Murdock, George P.; National Bureau of Standards ( see Bureau of Standards). (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - National Education Association. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, Task Force; Natinal Institute for Mental Health (see NIMH). (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - National Science Foundation, Evaluations. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - National Science Foundation, Grant Proposal (see also Boxes 28-30). 1970 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - National Science Foundation, Travel Grant Application. 1964 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Natural History. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Neutra, Richard, J.; Newman, M.W. (see Inland Architect). (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Nicoletti, Manfredi. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - NIMH, Grant Applications (see also Boxes 28-30). (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - NIMH Grant Application, Approved but Not Funded (see also Boxes 28-30). (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - NIMH Center for Studies of Metropolitan and Regional Mental Health Ad Hoc Committee. 1967-1969 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - NIMH Mental Health Small Grants Committee. 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - NIMH Metropolitan Mental Health Problems Review Committee. 1969-1973 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - NIMH Social Sciences Research Review Committee; Noise Abatement Hearing, EPA (see Environmental Protection Agency Noise Abatement Hearing. 1967-1969, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Nonverbal Communication Conference, Toronto. 1976 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Northeastern Illinois Metropolitan Area Planning Commission. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Northwestern University: Chandler, B.J., Dean, School of Education. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Northwestern University: Mack, Raymond, Provost. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Northwestern University: Roloff, Lee. (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Northwestern University: Strotz, Robert. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Northwestern University: Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Northwestern University: Business School (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Northwestern University: ETH Vita Supplements, Activities Reports, etc. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Northwestern University: Intersocietal Grant Studies. 1968 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Northwestern University: Research Proposal, Summer. 1968 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern University: Students, Mostly Undergraduates. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Northwestern University: Teacher Evaluation Letter to Laura Page. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Northwestern University: Anthropology Department, Beale, Helen (see also Box 36/ Folder 5). (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Northwestern University: Blakely, Thomas D. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Northwestern University: Evans, Cynthia Peters. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Northwestern University: Evans, Cynthia Peters (see also Box 35/Folder 14, Box 38/Folder 3-4). 1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Northwestern University: Evans, Cynthia Peters, NSF Grant Proposal. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Northwestern University: Levis-Matichek, Gladys. 1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Northwestern University: Levis-Matichek, Gladys (see also Box 35/Folder 2-3). 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Northwestern University: Silverman, Daniel A. (see also Box 35/Folder 13). (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Northwestern University: Stern, Gwen L. (see also Box 38/Folder 1). (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Northwestern University: Winfrey, Pat. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Northwestern University: (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Northwestern University: General Correspondence. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Northwestern University: Graduate Student Field Evaluations. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Northwestern University: Independent Study. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Oberg, Kalervo. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Office Design. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Oliver, Douglas. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Oltmans, Willem L. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Osmond, Humphrey. 1960-1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Osmond, Humphrey. 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Osmond, Humprey. 1971-- (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Parr, Albert E. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pawley, Eric. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Pegasus (Mobil Oil Magazine), Interview. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Pellow, Deborah. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Society of Architects, Talk. 1963 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Penny-Missouri Award. 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Percy, Charles H. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Perkins & Will/Philip Will, Jr. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia City Planing Commission. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Philadelphia Geriatric Center. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Playboy Article: "The Sounds of Silence;" Point IV (se Foreign Service Institute, Point VI. 1971 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Pomerance, Ralph. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Potter, Clarkson N; Price, Charlton R. (see Midwest Research Institute). (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Proxemics Data from Correspondents. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Proxemics Directory. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Proxemics Handbook Correspondence. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Pruitt Igoe Public Housing. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Pruitt Igoe Public Housing: Skidmore, Owings & Merrill. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Psychology Today, Interview by Ken Friedman. April 1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Psychology Today, Interview by Elizabeth Hall. 1976 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Publishers Other than Doubleday. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Rapoport, Amos. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Rapp, Stephanie and Mike. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Reader's Digest, Interview with John Lagemann. January 1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Reid, Whitelaw. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Requests for Training in Proxemics. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Research Proposals Evaluated by ETH (not NSF). (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Reviews in Anthropology. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Rice, Frank A. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Richardson, F.L.W., Jr. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Riesman, David. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Rioch, David McK. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Rodnich, David. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Rosenberg, Harold. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Ruder, William. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Scheflen, Albert E. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Scientific American. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Sebeok, Thomas A. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Senate Foreign Relations Committee. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Shane, Harold G. and June. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Shapiro, Harry L. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Sidman, Louis E. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Siegel, Arthur S.; The Silent Language (see Box 5/ Folder 1 and Boxes 41-41). (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Singer, Leonard. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Sivadon, Paul. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Skansie, Juli; Skidmore, Owings & Merrill (see Pruitt Igoe Public Housing.) (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Slovenko, Ralph. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Smith, Cloethiel Woodard. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Page. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Smithsonian Institution Symposium. February 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Society for Applied Anthropology. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Society for Technical Communication. (Box 15, Folder 5)